Denzel Udemba

Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA denzeludemba@gmail.com denzeludemba.com Highly skilled Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in crafting end-to-end business solutions. Proven experience in successfully leading and contributing to various software development initiatives, with a focus on modernizing applications, enhancing security, and improving overall system performance.

Work Experience

IRS Contractor Backend Engineer

Nikkyzam Consulting Services

Aug 2022 - Current

- Initiated and led SpringBoot 3 and JDK 17 upgrade for the in-app-notifications module, resulting in enhanced performance and compatibility with the latest Java technologies.
- Developed an SQL script for table creation and data population, following best practices in database design. Achieved a 15% increase in database query efficiency and overall system responsiveness.
- Collaborated with security personnel utilizing SonarQube to identify and rectify CWE-20 vulnerabilities in the codebase, achieving an 18% reduction in security vulnerabilities and enhanced code quality.
- Collaboratively with a 5-person engineering team to migrate SOAP Balance-Due microservice to a RESTful application, improving statelessness and system scalability.
- Partnered with senior engineers to develop a Spring Batch application for converting WSDL to JSON in order to provide mock TIN user data for the QA team. Reduced testing cycle time by 20% and improved the accuracy of test scenarios.

DevOps EngineerLTN Global
June 2019 - Feb 2022

- Designed System Architecture to facilitate SCTE104,35 & 224 Profiles for high-level broadcast companies including but not limited to Fox, AMC, Sinclair Broadcast, Singtel, Encompass Digital Media, Sling, Comcast & Werner Media
- Collaborated with stakeholders to understand unique requirements and tailored solutions to meet their broadcasting needs effectively.
- Utilized Ansible for provisioning, orchestrating, and deploying software solutions within the VMware vSphere environment.
- Spearheaded numerous projects requiring the migration of On-premises Servers to AWS EC2 Instances using Cloudformation Template
- Wrote Bash script for LTNs Video Metadata Analyzer to optimize SCTE104 Logger processes, reducing CPU Load by 60%

Skills —						
Spring Boot	Docker	Ansible	Python	Java	AWS (EC2, S3)	SonarQube
VMware Vsphere	Maven	CI/CD	Jenkins	Git	ELK	React
Education ————						

Major: B.S.E Electrical Engineering Mercer University Jan 2015-Dec 2018